choice.co.uk 2007-12-25

# Choice

 |   
| **Quick Links**  
---  
Safety of your details  
Unsubscribing  
Cookies  
Registered company details  
Terms & Conditions for this website  
Terms & Conditions for a credit account  
| 

Safety of your details

How safe are my transactions?  
Choice takes the security of your details very seriously. We use **industry standard** encryption methods to deter would-be hackers. 'Encryption' turns your information into a special code that only Choice computers can unscramble.

What information do you collect about me and why?  
Littlewoods Shop Direct Home Shopping Limited ("Littlewoods Shop Direct") provides your goods. The Littlewoods Shop Direct group of companies ("the Group") also includes Shop Direct Financial Services Limited, which provides your main catalogue credit account, subject to status, and arranges other financial services products, and Littlewoods Finance Company Limited, which may also offer you other credit facilities and/or financial products, subject to status. Both companies are subsidiaries of Everyday Financial Solutions Limited together known as "EFS". By giving information to Littlewoods Shop Direct and EFS you agree that it will be shared within the Littlewoods Shop Direct Group. A full list of Littlewoods Shop Direct Group companies is available from the Data Protection Unit, Littlewoods Shop Direct Home Shopping Limited, Park Lane, Netherton, Liverpool, L72 1LE.

Littlewoods Shop Direct and EFS may use your personal information as follows: 

  * To process your payments.
  * To fulfil your order and administer your account.
  * To pass information about you to agents, service providers and employees to carry out services. In the course of providing such services, we may transfer your personal information outside of the European Economic Area. We will employ appropriate security measures to protect your personal information where this is the case.
  * To disclose information about you to any relevant regulator if they require it or to anyone else if there is a legal duty to do so.
  * To run any prize draw or competition you may enter.
  * The information held about you, but not information held at credit reference agencies, may also be used to analyse your shopping preferences as part of Littlewoods Shop Direct's and EFS' marketing programmes. This may help them to select and tailor products, services or special discounts and to inform you about any of those Littlewoods Shop Direct or EFS think you will be interested to hear about.

| 

  * To send you brochures, leaflets, catalogues and other promotional material for our products and services. We may also telephone or email you to discuss account details or for market or service research. In addition, we may include leaflets or brochures for complementary products or services from third parties with our statements and parcels.
  * Littlewoods Shop Direct or EFS may pass your personal information to carefully selected third parties to use for marketing. Littlewoods Shop Direct, EFS or third party partners may contact you by mail, telephone, e-mail, text message or any other reasonable method. If you do not wish to be contacted by third parties in this way, or you do not want Littlewoods Shop Direct or EFS to contact you for their marketing or if you have any queries about data protection, please call freephone 0800 051 1213.
  * The Group may monitor or record telephone conversations with you to ensure consistent services levels, to prevent or detect fraud and for training purposes.
  * Littlewoods Shop Direct and EFS may also pass your information to other businesses within the Group, and to third parties, for debtor tracing and debt recovery purposes.

Data Protection explained  
In summary, we are committed to protecting your privacy. We use information we collect on the site to make shopping with us possible and to enhance your overall shopping experience. We welcome your questions and comments about any topic, including Data Protection and your privacy, by email.  
---|---  
  
Credit Applications

  * If you apply for credit EFS will search your record at a credit reference agency or agencies who will supply EFS with credit information as well as information from the electoral register. EFS will use credit scoring methods to assess your application and to verify your identity. Credit searches and other information which is provided to EFS and/or the credit reference agencies about you and those with whom you are financially linked may be used by EFS and other companies if credit decisions are made about you or other members of your household. You are linked with another individual by means of a joint credit application or running a joint credit account. Even if your application goes no further, the credit reference agencies will add details of this search and your application to your record.
  * In assessing you for credit and to manage your account EFS may also use any information which the Group already holds about you.
  * EFS may occasionally search your records with the credit reference agencies so they can manage your account and take further decisions about credit. These searches will not be available to other lenders for credit assessment purposes
  * If EFS enters into a credit agreement with you they will also add details of your agreement as well as ongoing details of your account and how you manage it to credit reference agency records. If you do not repay on time or in full they will tell the credit reference agencies who will record details of the debt. All this information will be seen by other organisations carrying out later searches and EFS may also share it directly within the Group. The information may be used to assess you for credit or to verify your identity.

Fraud Prevention

For everyone's protection, we check the details of every first order with the fraud prevention agencies and these checks may be repeated with future orders. The Group may also use the information you have given, or which the Group already holds about you.

If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies.

Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information.

We and other organisations may access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when: 

  * Checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other facilities;
  * Managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
  * Recovering debt;
  * Checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; 
  * Checking details of job applicants and employees

We and other organisations may also access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies.  
|  Please telephone freephone 0800 092 9054 if you want to have details of those credit reference and fraud prevention agencies from whom EFS obtains and to whom EFS gives information about you. You have a legal right to these details. EFS, credit reference and fraud prevention agencies and other home shopping traders may also use the records for statistical analysis about credit, insurance and fraud.

Littlewoods Shop Direct and EFS may use automated decision making systems when assessing you for credit and for fraud prevention.

Payment by Cheque  
If you pay by cheque we may use the Transax service, provided by Certegy Limited, to help us in deciding whether to accept your cheque. If your cheque is dishonoured, we will inform Certegy and also provide them with any information we hold (including your name and address). We may assign our rights to collect a debt to Certegy Limited. Certegy will hold information about you in order to enable them to collect a debt and may carry out a credit check where they deem it necessary to facilitate collection. Certegy will record information in relation to any cheque it is asked to guarantee and will use it to decide whether to guarantee future cheques where a subscribing organisation requests such information to assist it in deciding whether to accept a cheque as a payment. Certegy will charge an administration fee for the collection of a dishonoured cheque.

In the event that you have any questions about the personal information held by Certegy that relates to you, or for details of the Credit Reference Agency they use, please phone 0870 240 4222.

Insurance Policies, Extended Guarantees and Shopping Insurance  
Your insurance policy or service plan will be set up by EFS. Your information may be used as detailed above and may also be passed to insurers (for insurance applications only), service plan providers (in both cases for administration purposes) and relevant regulators.

Can I access the information you hold about me?  
Yes, you can obtain details of the personal information we hold on you by contacting us at Data Protection Unit, Choice, Park Lane, Netherton, Liverpool, L72 1LE. Alternatively, please email us at [queries@choice.co.uk](mailto:queries@choice.co.uk). There is a statutory fee for access to your information, currently £10.  
  
---|---
